<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Uncategorized &#8211; Vinay Kumar</title>
	<atom:link href="/category/uncategorized/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link></link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 30 May 2024 07:25:08 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.5.3</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Heartful latest Look and progress</title>
		<link>/heartful-latest-look-and-progress/</link>
					<comments>/heartful-latest-look-and-progress/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[vinay]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2024 07:21:14 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=3093</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Completed enemy and player state machines and added attack and jump facilities used animation states to make enemy ai.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="wp-block-video"><video autoplay controls loop src="/wp-content/uploads/2024/05/movie_002-1.mp4"></video></figure>



<p>Completed enemy and player state machines and added attack and jump facilities</p>



<p>used animation states to make enemy ai.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/heartful-latest-look-and-progress/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		<enclosure url="/wp-content/uploads/2024/05/movie_002-1.mp4" length="892207" type="video/mp4" />

			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Speaking Lanterns</title>
		<link>/speaking-lanterns/</link>
					<comments>/speaking-lanterns/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[vinay]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2024 07:11:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=3088</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Speaking Lantern is a game where you have to find all the missing lantern scattered around in an open terrain in a first person perspective]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Speaking Lantern is a game where you have to find all the missing lantern scattered around in an open terrain in a first person perspective</p>



<figure class="wp-block-video"><video autoplay loop src="/wp-content/uploads/2024/05/1683616653933.mp4"></video></figure>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/speaking-lanterns/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		<enclosure url="/wp-content/uploads/2024/05/1683616653933.mp4" length="3846081" type="video/mp4" />

			</item>
		<item>
		<title>AA replica</title>
		<link>/aa-replica/</link>
					<comments>/aa-replica/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[vinay]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2024 07:07:27 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=3082</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The AA game replica is a minimalist and addictive arcade game that tests players&#8217; precision and timing. The core gameplay involves shooting small numbered balls, referred to as pins, onto a rotating large ball in the center without hitting the other pins already attached to it. Each level requires a specific number of pins to [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="wp-block-video"><video autoplay loop muted src="/wp-content/uploads/2024/05/WhatsApp-Video-2024-05-30-at-12.33.00.mp4"></video></figure>



<p>The AA game replica is a minimalist and addictive arcade game that tests players&#8217; precision and timing. The core gameplay involves shooting small numbered balls, referred to as pins, onto a rotating large ball in the center without hitting the other pins already attached to it. Each level requires a specific number of pins to be attached, and as the game progresses, the rotating ball changes speed and direction, increasing the difficulty. The game’s simple tap-to-shoot controls make it easy to pick up, but the escalating challenge ensures that players remain engaged. The sleek design, combined with its straightforward yet challenging mechanics, makes the AA game replica a captivating experience that appeals to players looking for a quick and fun test of their reflexes and accuracy.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/aa-replica/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		<enclosure url="/wp-content/uploads/2024/05/WhatsApp-Video-2024-05-30-at-12.33.00.mp4" length="1475348" type="video/mp4" />

			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Cut the rope replica</title>
		<link>/cut-the-rope-replica/</link>
					<comments>/cut-the-rope-replica/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[vinay]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2024 06:59:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=3077</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Cut the Rope replica is a delightful puzzle game that revolves around feeding a cute, green creature named Om Nom by delivering candy to its mouth. The gameplay involves strategically cutting ropes and manipulating various objects to navigate the candy past obstacles and towards Om Nom. Each level presents a unique challenge, requiring players [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="wp-block-video"><video autoplay loop src="/wp-content/uploads/2024/05/Cut_001-1.mp4"></video></figure>



<p>The Cut the Rope replica is a delightful puzzle game that revolves around feeding a cute, green creature named Om Nom by delivering candy to its mouth. The gameplay involves strategically cutting ropes and manipulating various objects to navigate the candy past obstacles and towards Om Nom. Each level presents a unique challenge, requiring players to think creatively and use precise timing to solve the puzzles. As players advance through the game, new mechanics and obstacles are introduced, including bubbles, spikes, and floating platforms, enhancing the complexity and variety of the puzzles. Collecting stars in each level adds an extra layer of difficulty and replayability, encouraging players to perfect their techniques. With its charming graphics, intuitive touch controls, and progressively challenging levels, the Cut the Rope replica provides an engaging and satisfying puzzle-solving experience for players of all ages.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/cut-the-rope-replica/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		<enclosure url="/wp-content/uploads/2024/05/Cut_001-1.mp4" length="1506132" type="video/mp4" />

			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Color Switch</title>
		<link>/color-switch/</link>
					<comments>/color-switch/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[vinay]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2024 06:52:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=3073</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Color Switch replica is a vibrant and engaging mobile game that challenges players to navigate a bouncing ball through a series of multicolored obstacles. The main objective is to match the color of the ball with the segments of the obstacles to pass through them. As the game progresses, the speed and complexity of [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="wp-block-video"><video autoplay loop src="/wp-content/uploads/2024/05/movie_002.mp4"></video></figure>



<p>The Color Switch replica is a vibrant and engaging mobile game that challenges players to navigate a bouncing ball through a series of multicolored obstacles. The main objective is to match the color of the ball with the segments of the obstacles to pass through them. As the game progresses, the speed and complexity of the obstacles increase, requiring quick reflexes and precise timing. The game features various levels, each with unique patterns and challenges, ensuring a dynamic and addictive gameplay experience. Players can also collect stars to unlock new ball designs and other cosmetic features, adding an extra layer of customization and achievement. The intuitive one-tap control mechanism makes the game accessible to players of all ages, while the escalating difficulty keeps them coming back for more.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/color-switch/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		<enclosure url="/wp-content/uploads/2024/05/movie_002.mp4" length="1753831" type="video/mp4" />

			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Sword Fight Simulator</title>
		<link>/sword-fight-simulator/</link>
					<comments>/sword-fight-simulator/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[vinay]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2024 14:43:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=3011</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Abstract: In this paper, we embark on a journey to explore the intricate development and implementation of an augmented reality-virtual reality (AR-VR) survival gameplay experience set within a dynamic circular arena. By leveraging cutting-edge technologies and innovative game design principles, we aim to redefine the boundaries of immersion and engagement in gaming. Through a comprehensive [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><strong>Abstract</strong>: In this paper, we embark on a journey to explore the intricate development and implementation of an augmented reality-virtual reality (AR-VR) survival gameplay experience set within a dynamic circular arena. By leveraging cutting-edge technologies and innovative game design principles, we aim to redefine the boundaries of immersion and engagement in gaming. Through a comprehensive examination of the game&#8217;s design, mechanics, technology integration, and potential impact on the gaming industry, this paper offers insights into the evolving landscape of immersive entertainment.</p>



<p><strong><em>Keywords: AR-VR, Gameplay, Survival, Circular Arena, Immersive Experience</em></strong>.</p>



<p><strong>I.&nbsp; INTRODUCTION</strong></p>



<p>The gaming industry is undergoing a profound transformation, driven by advancements in technology and an increasing demand for immersive experiences. This paper introduces a groundbreaking project that combines the immersive capabilities of augmented reality (AR) and virtual reality (VR) to create a dynamic survival gameplay experience. Set within a circular arena, players are thrust into a relentless battle against respawning enemies, challenging their skills, reflexes, and strategic thinking. By pushing the boundaries of technology and creativity, this project aims to deliver a gaming experience that captivates players and sets new standards for immersion and engagement.</p>



<p><strong>II. </strong>&nbsp;<strong>LITERATURE</strong> <strong>REVIEW</strong></p>



<p>The foundation of this project is built upon a thorough review of existing literature in the fields of AR-VR gaming, survival gameplay mechanics, and immersive environments. Previous studies have highlighted the potential of AR and VR technologies to create captivating gaming experiences that blur the lines between the virtual and real worlds. Additionally, research on survival gameplay mechanics has demonstrated the effectiveness of dynamic challenges, such as respawning enemies, in enhancing player engagement and immersion. By synthesizing insights from these diverse areas of study, this project seeks to leverage the strengths of each to craft a truly compelling gaming experience.</p>



<p><strong>III. </strong>&nbsp;<strong>PROBLEM STATEMENT</strong></p>



<p>The modern era witnesses a surge in the craving for immersive escapism, where individuals seek solace from the mundane through virtual adventures. Among these desires, there exists a prevalent yearning to inhabit the persona of a swordsman, to wield a blade with mastery, and traverse fantastical realms in epic battles. However, current solutions fail to fully realize these aspirations, offering mere glimpses of immersion and leaving users disenchanted with shallow experiences.</p>



<p>Users lament the lack of depth and realism in existing virtual swordsmanship simulations, which often feel detached and unfulfilling. The desire to be transported into a truly immersive world, where every swing of the sword resonates with tangible weight and consequence, remains unmet. Moreover, the absence of seamless integration between the physical and virtual realms inhibits users from fully embodying their chosen role, detracting from the overall immersion and satisfaction of the experience.</p>



<p>Hence, there is an urgent need for a solution that transcends the limitations of current technologies, offering users a truly immersive and empowering journey into the world of swordsmanship. This solution must seamlessly blend virtual and physical elements, providing users with an authentic and transformative experience that fulfills their deepest desires and transports them into a new realm of adventure and discovery.</p>



<p><strong>IV.</strong> <strong>REQUIREMENTS</strong></p>



<ul>
<li>Required Hardware components<ul><li>Processor – Intel i5, equivalent or greater</li></ul><ul><li>Graphic Ram – NVidia gta 970 or greater</li></ul><ul><li>8gb ram</li></ul>
<ul>
<li>Oculus quest 2 or HTC vive</li>
</ul>
</li>



<li>Required Software:</li>



<li>Unity 3d</li>



<li>Blender 3d</li>



<li>Adobe Substance Painter</li>



<li>Marvelous Designer</li>



<li>FL studio</li>



<li>Zbrush</li>



<li>Technologies:</li>



<li>Unity</li>



<li>VR</li>



<li>3d modeling and texturing</li>
</ul>



<p><strong>V.</strong> <strong>METHODOLOGY</strong></p>



<ol>
<li><strong>Game Design:</strong> The core of the project revolves around designing a circular arena environment that is visually stunning and conducive to intense gameplay. This includes conceptualizing the arena layout, enemy placement, and environmental elements.</li>



<li><strong>AR-VR Integration:</strong> AR technology overlays virtual elements onto the player&#8217;s real-world  environment, while VR technology transports players into a fully immersive virtual space. Integration of these technologies requires careful consideration of hardware compatibility, tracking systems, and user interface design.</li>



<li><strong>Enemy Respawning:</strong> A sophisticated respawn system is implemented to ensure that enemies continuously pose a threat to the player. This involves designing AI algorithms to control enemy behavior, managing spawn points, and adjusting difficulty dynamically based on player performance.</li>



<li><strong>Player Interaction:</strong> Players interact with the game using motion controllers or gestures, allowing for intuitive navigation and combat mechanics. User interface design plays a crucial role in facilitating seamless interaction and providing feedback to the player.</li>



<li><strong>Scoring System:</strong> A robust scoring system tracks the player&#8217;s survival time, providing feedback and incentives for prolonged gameplay sessions. This includes leaderboard integration, achievement systems, and rewards for achieving milestones.</li>
</ol>



<p><strong>VI. RESULTS</strong></p>



<p>The culmination of extensive development efforts is a gaming experience that transcends traditional boundaries, offering players an adrenaline-fueled journey into the heart of immersive entertainment. The seamless integration of AR and VR technologies creates a sense of presence and immersion that is unparalleled in the gaming landscape. The dynamic nature of the circular arena and the relentless onslaught of respawning enemies keep players on the edge of their seats, challenging them to push their limits and test their skills. Early user testing and feedback have been overwhelmingly positive, highlighting the potential of this project to leave a lasting impact on the gaming industry.</p>



<p><strong>VII. CONCLUSION &amp; FUTURE SCOPE</strong></p>



<p>In conclusion, the AR-VR survival gameplay experience represents a significant milestone in the evolution of immersive entertainment. By harnessing the power of cutting-edge technologies and innovative game design principles, this project has created a gaming experience that captivates players and pushes the boundaries of immersion and engagement. As technology continues to advance and evolve, the potential for AR-VR gaming to revolutionize the entertainment industry is limitless. By embracing creativity, innovation, and collaboration, developers can continue to redefine the gaming landscape and inspire players worldwide.</p>



<p><strong>Project Screenshots</strong></p>



<div class="wp-block-uagb-image uagb-block-39b681ef wp-block-uagb-image--layout-default wp-block-uagb-image--effect-static wp-block-uagb-image--align-none"><figure class="wp-block-uagb-image__figure"><img decoding="async" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2024/05/GameSS-1.png ,/wp-content/uploads/2024/05/GameSS-1.png 780w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/05/GameSS-1.png 360w" sizes="(max-width: 480px) 150px" src="/wp-content/uploads/2024/05/GameSS-1.png" alt="" class="uag-image-3012" width="1428" height="872" title="GameSS-1" loading="lazy" role="img"/></figure></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/sword-fight-simulator/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Heartful (Work in Progress)</title>
		<link>/heartful-work-in-progress/</link>
					<comments>/heartful-work-in-progress/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[vinay]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2024 20:31:17 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=2974</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Concept Working title&#160; Heartful High Level Concept/Design&#160; Concept statement&#160; 2d side scroller metroidvania game, that gives hack and slash game contesting mental health issues and feeling of loneliness and the concept of finding yourself back without being consumed with negativity. Genre(s)&#160; &#160;The game is a 2d side scroller metroidvania .&#160; Target audience&#160; The game targets [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<h1 class="wp-block-heading">Concept</h1>



<p><strong>Working title&nbsp;</strong></p>



<p><em>Heartful</em></p>



<p><sub>High Level Concept/Desig</sub>n&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Concept statement&nbsp;</strong></p>



<p><em>2d side scroller metroidvania game, that gives hack and slash game contesting mental health issues and feeling of loneliness and the concept of finding yourself back without being consumed with negativity.</em></p>



<p><strong>Genre(s)&nbsp;</strong></p>



<p><em>&nbsp;The game is a 2d side scroller metroidvania .&nbsp;</em></p>



<p><strong>Target audience&nbsp;</strong></p>



<p><em>The game targets audience from children to adults . The game is aiming to&nbsp; ESRB rating of everyone 10+</em><em>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; </em><em>&nbsp; (E10+)</em></p>



<p><strong>Unique Selling Points&nbsp;</strong></p>



<p><em>The Unique feature in this game is that it teaches about life lesson about “<strong><u>Not letting negative thoughts/emotions control you and finding the parts of you that&nbsp; you lost</u></strong>” this game is only one of the few games that came out in India that is not only fun to play but also motivates people who might be struggling to reach out and ask for help.</em></p>



<p><strong>Player Experience and Game POV&nbsp;</strong></p>



<p><em>Player is a boy/girl who’s heart is broken into pieces by an dark being(of opposite gender) and the player sets out into the journey to find those missing parts, of himself/herself trying to avoid getting hit by the enemies that increases the darkness level of the player when full the player turns into an dark being themselves resulting in a Game Over.&nbsp; In the way player can remove the damage by meeting “<u>friend</u>s” a group of npcs that help the player to get over their negativity</em></p>



<p><strong>Visual and Audio Style&nbsp;</strong></p>



<p><em>The Visual style would be abstract art style with minimalist character and other design. And the audio style would be healing soft instrumental piano beats but intense cello/violin will accompany the rhythm transitioning into combat intense areas.</em></p>



<p><em>&nbsp;&nbsp;</em><sub>Product Desig</sub>n&nbsp;</p>



<p><em>The game is heavily inspired from Gris by Nomada studios and Worldless from Noname Studios</em></p>



<div class="wp-block-uagb-image aligncenter uagb-block-84af0516 wp-block-uagb-image--layout-default wp-block-uagb-image--effect-static wp-block-uagb-image--align-center"><figure class="wp-block-uagb-image__figure"><img decoding="async" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2024/05/refrence.png ,/wp-content/uploads/2024/05/refrence.png 780w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/05/refrence.png 360w" sizes="(max-width: 480px) 150px" src="/wp-content/uploads/2024/05/refrence.png" alt="" class="uag-image-3021" width="675" height="381" title="refrence" loading="lazy" role="img"/></figure></div>



<div class="wp-block-uagb-image aligncenter uagb-block-17fca797 wp-block-uagb-image--layout-default wp-block-uagb-image--effect-static wp-block-uagb-image--align-center"><figure class="wp-block-uagb-image__figure"><img decoding="async" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2024/05/references2.png ,/wp-content/uploads/2024/05/references2.png 780w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/05/references2.png 360w" sizes="(max-width: 480px) 150px" src="/wp-content/uploads/2024/05/references2.png" alt="" class="uag-image-3024" width="675" height="381" title="references2" loading="lazy" role="img"/></figure></div>



<p><strong>Game World Fiction&nbsp;</strong></p>



<p><em>The game takes place in a bright monochromatic worlds that are divided into 4 different regions containing different parts of players heart and each heart peace will give player a new ability. That helps the player to progress to next level and solve different puzzles inside the game finally reaching out to the end completing the heart.&nbsp;</em></p>



<p><strong>Monetization&nbsp;</strong></p>



<p><em>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; </em><em>The game would be launched onto steam with a price to pay and we would also have ingame purchase/donations for different skins and DLCs that would improve the user experience.</em></p>



<p><strong>Platform(s), Technology, and Scope (brief)&nbsp;</strong></p>



<p><em>First version would be made using unity and released on steam for the players to improve the game with bugs and other problems and then 2nd release for mobile devices&nbsp; on android and ios devices</em></p>



<p><strong>Core Loops&nbsp;</strong></p>



<p><em>The player completes every level by finding a part of their heart. Main Game play loop would be defeating enemies and solving puzzles to get over new obstacles and new challenges and dealing with newer enemies and unlocking other areas&nbsp;</em></p>



<p><sub>Detailed &amp; Game Systems Desig</sub>n</p>



<p><strong>Objectives and Progression&nbsp;</strong></p>



<p><em>The main objective of the Game is to find all pieces of player’s heart and unlocking new areas.</em></p>



<p><strong>Game Systems&nbsp;</strong></p>



<p><em>The player instinctively uses a controller or a keyboard to interact with objects or attack enemies&nbsp;&nbsp;</em></p>



<h1 class="wp-block-heading">Art Style</h1>



<p><strong>Warli</strong> art. An art form that is driven by everyday life stories and these tales also in turn become a reminder of traditional values and cultures cherished by the tribe. The Warlis believe that without the ahankaar, there is no kahankar. They have an advanced notion of communication. A story is not just a story, it is the passing of energy from narrator to listener.</p>



<div class="wp-block-uagb-image aligncenter uagb-block-a7d6de06 wp-block-uagb-image--layout-default wp-block-uagb-image--effect-static wp-block-uagb-image--align-center"><figure class="wp-block-uagb-image__figure"><img decoding="async" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2024/05/deccan1.png ,/wp-content/uploads/2024/05/deccan1.png 780w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/05/deccan1.png 360w" sizes="(max-width: 480px) 150px" src="/wp-content/uploads/2024/05/deccan1.png" alt="" class="uag-image-3025" width="339" height="222" title="deccan1" loading="lazy" role="img"/></figure></div>



<div class="wp-block-uagb-image aligncenter uagb-block-1facdbf3 wp-block-uagb-image--layout-default wp-block-uagb-image--effect-static wp-block-uagb-image--align-center"><figure class="wp-block-uagb-image__figure"><img decoding="async" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2024/05/deccan.png ,/wp-content/uploads/2024/05/deccan.png 780w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/05/deccan.png 360w" sizes="(max-width: 480px) 150px" src="/wp-content/uploads/2024/05/deccan.png" alt="" class="uag-image-3026" width="194" height="411" title="deccan" loading="lazy" role="img"/></figure></div>



<h1 class="wp-block-heading">Game mechanics</h1>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Core Game mechanics And Key maps</h2>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Movement</h3>



<p>The Core game mechanics for the came would be movement through wasd that will give 4 main areas</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; 1. W- look up&nbsp; (tilt the camera a bit upward)</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; 2. S- look down (tilt camera a bit downwards)</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; 3. A – Move player Left</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; 4. D – Move player Right</p>



<p>And similar controls for a controller through joystick</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Attack</h3>



<p>The main attack button for attacking would be one button i.e &#8211;</p>



<p>‘B’ on controller for attack</p>



<p>‘left mouse button’&nbsp; on the mouse</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Abilities</h2>



<p>There will be a number of abilities</p>



<ol>
<li>Meele attack</li>



<li>Long range attack</li>



<li>Double jump</li>



<li>Dash</li>
</ol>



<h1 class="wp-block-heading">Enemies</h1>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Basic Enemies</h2>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Type 1</h3>



<p>&nbsp; Type 1 enemies are basic enemies that function on the ground and does melee damage</p>



<ul>
<li>Frog</li>



<li>Duck</li>



<li>Cow</li>
</ul>



<p>Frog is the first enemy player would encounter and will need to defeat in order to progress</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Type 2</h3>



<p>Type 2 Enemies are also basic enemies and they will deal long range damage with projectiles etc..</p>



<div class="wp-block-uagb-buttons uagb-buttons__outer-wrap uagb-btn__default-btn uagb-btn-tablet__default-btn uagb-btn-mobile__default-btn uagb-block-d2844539"><div class="uagb-buttons__wrap uagb-buttons-layout-wrap ">
<div class="wp-block-uagb-buttons-child uagb-buttons__outer-wrap uagb-block-dde001fe wp-block-button"><div class="uagb-button__wrapper"><a class="uagb-buttons-repeater wp-block-button__link" aria-label="" href="#" rel="follow noopener" target="_self" role="button"><div class="uagb-button__link">Visit Git</div></a></div></div>
</div></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/heartful-work-in-progress/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Hello world!</title>
		<link>/hello-world/</link>
					<comments>/hello-world/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[vinay]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2024 06:59:55 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=1</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Welcome to WordPress. This is your first post. Edit or delete it, then start writing!]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Welcome to WordPress. This is your first post. Edit or delete it, then start writing!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/hello-world/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
